caws.ws 2019-06-15

# CAWs.ws

This Privacy Policy describes how your personal information is collected, used, and shared when you visit http://caws.ws/ (the “Site”).

The processing of personal data, such as the name and e-mail address of a website user shall always be in line with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), and in accordance with the country-specific data protection regulations applicable to CAWs.ws. By means of this data protection declaration, CAWs.ws would like to inform the general public of the nature, scope, and purpose of the personal data we collect, use and process. Furthermore, website users are informed, by means of this data protection declaration, of the rights to which they are entitled.

## PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT

When you visit the Site, we automatically collect certain information about your device, including information about your web browser, IP address, time zone, and some of the cookies that are installed on your device. Additionally, as you browse the Site, we collect information about the individual web pages or products that you view, what websites or search terms referred you to the Site, and information about how you interact with the Site. We refer to this automatically-collected information as “Device Information.”

We collect Device Information using the following technologies:

\- “Cookies” are data files that are placed on your device or computer and often include an anonymous unique identifier. For more information about cookies, and how to disable cookies, visit http://www.allaboutcookies.org.  
\- “Log files” track actions occurring on the Site, and collect data including your IP address, browser type, Internet service provider, referring/exit pages, and date/time stamps.  
\- “Web beacons,” “tags,” and “pixels” are electronic files used to record information about how you browse the Site.

## COOKIES

CAWs.ws uses cookies. Cookies are text files that are stored in a computer system via an Internet browser.

A cookie consists of information sent by a web server to a web browser, and stored by the browser. The information is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. This enables the web server to identify and track the web browser.

We may use both “session” cookies and “persistent” cookies on the website. We will use the session cookies to: keep track of you whilst you navigate the website. We will use the persistent cookies to: enable our website to recognise you when you visit.

Session cookies will be deleted from your computer when you close your browser. Persistent cookies will remain stored on your computer until deleted, or until they reach a specified expiry date.

Many Internet sites and servers use cookies. Many cookies contain a so-called cookie ID. A cookie ID is a unique identifier of the cookie. It consists of a character string through which Internet pages and servers can be assigned to the specific Internet browser in which the cookie was stored. This allows visited Internet sites and servers to differentiate the individual browser of the dats subject from other Internet browsers that contain other cookies. A specific Internet browser can be recognized and identified using the unique cookie ID.

Through the use of cookies, CAWs.ws can provide the users of this website with more user-friendly services that would not be possible without the cookie setting.

By means of a cookie, the information and offers on our website can be optimized with the user in mind. Cookies allow us, as previously mentioned, to recognize our website users. The purpose of this recognition is to make it easier for users to utilise our website, particularly for interactive features such as registering an account, logging in, posting on the forum and leaving comments.

The website user may, at any time, prevent the setting of cookies through our website by means of a corresponding setting of the Internet browser used, and may thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Furthermore, already set cookies may be deleted at any time via an Internet browser or other software programs. This is possible in all popular Internet browsers. If the website user deactivates the setting of cookies in the Internet browser used, not all functions of our website may be entirely usable.

## ACCOUNT REGISTRATION

The website user has the possibility to register on this website with the indication of personal data. Which personal data are transmitted to CAWs.ws is determined by the respective input mask used for the registration. The personal data entered by the website user are collected and stored exclusively for internal use by CAWs.ws, and for CAWs.ws' own purposes. CAWs.ws may request transfer to one or more processors (e.g. an anti-spam service) that also uses personal data for an internal purpose which is attributable to CAWs.ws.

By registering on this website, the IP address—assigned by the Internet service provider (ISP) and used by the website user—date, and time of the registration are also stored. The storage of this data takes place against the background that this is the only way to prevent the misuse of our services, and, if necessary, to make it possible to investigate committed offenses. Insofar, the storage of this data is necessary to secure CAWs.ws. This data is not passed on to third parties unless there is a statutory obligation to pass on the data, or if the transfer serves the aim of criminal prosecution.

The registration of the website user, with the voluntary indication of personal data, is intended to enable CAWs.ws to offer the website user contents or services that may only be offered to registered users due to the nature of the matter in question. Registered persons are free to change the personal data specified during the registration at any time, or to have them completely deleted from the data stock of CAWs.ws.

CAWs.ws shall, at any time, provide information upon request to each website user as to what personal data are stored about the website user. In addition, the data controller shall correct or erase personal data at the request or indication of the website user, insofar as there are no statutory storage obligations.

## USE OF FORUM, COMMUNITY & COMMENTS

Personal details you give us when you sign up will be used solely for the purposes of forum functionality. Any information about you that you decide to post on the forum is considered to be 'publicly available' as it will have been indexed by Google (and other search engines) as well as online archive websites.

If you would like to remove your account, please email tom@caws.ws. Your posts will remain publicly available but your account and profile page will be removed from our database.  
If you would like to remove other personally identifying information from the forum pages, please send a link to the affected page and we will remove or redact it.

If a website user leaves a comment on the blog or forum published on this website, the comments made by the website user are also stored and published, as well as information on the date of the commentary and on the user's (pseudonym) chosen by the website user. In addition, the IP address assigned by the Internet service provider (ISP) to the website user is also logged. This storage of the IP address takes place for security reasons, and in case the website user violates the rights of third parties, or posts illegal content through a given comment. The storage of these personal data is, therefore, in the own interest of CAWs.ws, so that we can exculpate in the event of an infringement.

Email and IP addresses are checked with CleanTalk for anti-spam purposes. CleanTalk is a third party service and their privacy policy can be found here: https://cleantalk.org/publicoffer#privacy

Upon registering on the forum, your email address will be used to send a verification email to confirm your account, and remain linked to the account as a means of identifying that the account belongs to you, and so that you may use features such as the forgotten password reset. You will only receive operational emails, as well as notifications of new messages or replies if you choose to opt in to those. You may opt out of notifications at any time using the options provided within your account management page.

## GOOGLE ADSENSE

On this website, CAWs.ws has integrated Google AdSense. Google AdSense is an online service which allows the placement of advertising on third-party sites. Google AdSense is based on an algorithm that selects advertisements displayed on third-party sites to match with the content of the respective third-party site. Google AdSense allows an interest-based targeting of the Internet user, which is implemented by means of generating individual user profiles. 

The operating company of Google's AdSense component is Alphabet Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Pkwy, Mountain View, CA 94043-1351, United States.

The purpose of Google's AdSense component is the integration of advertisements on our website. Google AdSense places a cookie on the information technology system of the website user. The definition of cookies is explained above. With the setting of the cookie, Alphabet Inc. is enabled to analyze the use of our website. With each call-up to one of the individual pages of this Internet site, which is operated by CAWs.ws and into which a Google AdSense component is integrated, the Internet browser on the information technology system of the website user will automatically submit data through the Google AdSense component for the purpose of online advertising and the settlement of commissions to Alphabet Inc. During the course of this technical procedure, the enterprise Alphabet Inc. gains knowledge of personal data, such as the IP address of the website user, which serves Alphabet Inc., inter alia, to understand the origin of visitors and clicks and subsequently create commission settlements.

The website user may, as stated above, prevent the setting of cookies through our website at any time by means of a corresponding adjustment of the web browser used and thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Such an adjustment to the Internet browser used would also prevent Alphabet Inc. from setting a cookie on the information technology system of the website user. Additionally, cookies already in use by Alphabet Inc. may be deleted at any time via a web browser or other software programs.

Furthermore, Google AdSense also uses so-called tracking pixels. A tracking pixel is a miniature graphic that is embedded in web pages to enable a log file recording and a log file analysis through which a statistical analysis may be performed. Based on the embedded tracking pixels, Alphabet Inc. is able to determine if and when a website was opened by a website user, and which links were clicked on by the website user. Tracking pixels serve, inter alia, to analyze the flow of visitors on a website.

Through Google AdSense, personal data and information—which also includes the IP address, and is necessary for the collection and accounting of the displayed advertisements—is transmitted to Alphabet Inc. in the United States of America. These personal data will be stored and processed in the United States of America. The Alphabet Inc. may disclose the collected personal data through this technical procedure to third parties.

Google AdSense is further explained under the following link https://www.google.com/intl/en/adsense/start/.

## GOOGLE ANALYTICS

On this website, CAWs.ws has integrated the component of Google Analytics (with the anonymizer function). Google Analytics is a web analytics service. Web analytics is the collection, gathering, and analysis of data about the behavior of visitors to websites. A web analysis service collects, inter alia, data about the website from which a person has come (the so-called referrer), which sub-pages were visited, or how often and for what duration a sub-page was viewed. Web analytics are mainly used for the optimization of a website and in order to carry out a cost-benefit analysis of Internet advertising.

The operator of the Google Analytics component is Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Pkwy, Mountain View, CA 94043-1351, United States.

For the web analytics through Google Analytics CAWs.ws uses the application "_gat. _anonymizeIp". By means of this application the IP address of the Internet connection of the website user is abridged by Google and anonymised when accessing our websites from a Member State of the European Union or another Contracting State to the Agreement on the European Economic Area.

The purpose of the Google Analytics component is to analyze the traffic on our website. Google uses the collected data and information, inter alia, to evaluate the use of our website and to provide online reports, which show the activities on our websites, and to provide other services concerning the use of our Internet site for us.

Google Analytics places a cookie on the information technology system of the website user. The definition of cookies is explained above. With the setting of the cookie, Google is enabled to analyze the use of our website. With each call-up to one of the individual pages of this Internet site, which is operated by CAWs.ws and into which a Google Analytics component was integrated, the Internet browser on the information technology system of the website user will automatically submit data through the Google Analytics component for the purpose of online advertising and the settlement of commissions to Google. During the course of this technical procedure, the enterprise Google gains knowledge of personal information, such as the IP address of the website user, which serves Google, inter alia, to understand the origin of visitors and clicks, and subsequently create commission settlements.

The cookie is used to store personal information, such as the access time, the location from which the access was made, and the frequency of visits of our website by the website user. With each visit to our Internet site, such personal data, including the IP address of the Internet access used by the website user, will be transmitted to Google in the United States of America. These personal data are stored by Google in the United States of America. Google may pass these personal data collected through the technical procedure to third parties.

The website user may, as stated above, prevent the setting of cookies through our website at any time by means of a corresponding adjustment of the web browser used and thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Such an adjustment to the Internet browser used would also prevent Google Analytics from setting a cookie on the information technology system of the website user. In addition, cookies already in use by Google Analytics may be deleted at any time via a web browser or other software programs.

In addition, the website user has the possibility of objecting to a collection of data that are generated by Google Analytics, which is related to the use of this website, as well as the processing of this data by Google and the chance to preclude any such. For this purpose, the website user must download a browser add-on under the link https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout and install it. This browser add-on tells Google Analytics through a JavaScript, that any data and information about the visits of Internet pages may not be transmitted to Google Analytics. The installation of the browser add-ons is considered an objection by Google. If the information technology system of the website user is later deleted, formatted, or newly installed, then the website user must reinstall the browser add-ons to disable Google Analytics. If the browser add-on was uninstalled by the website user or any other person who is attributable to their sphere of competence, or is disabled, it is possible to execute the reinstallation or reactivation of the browser add-ons.

Further information and the applicable data protection provisions of Google may be retrieved under https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/ and under http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html. Google Analytics is further explained under the following Link https://www.google.com/analytics/.

## DO NOT TRACK

Please note that we do not alter our Site’s data collection and use practices when we see a Do Not Track signal from your browser.

## DISCLOSURES

We may disclose information about you to any of our employees, officers, agents, suppliers or subcontractors insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes as set out in this privacy policy.

In addition, we may disclose information about you:  
(a) to the extent that we are required to do so by law;  
(b) in connection with any legal proceedings or prospective legal proceedings;  
(c) in order to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights (including providing information to others for the purposes of fraud prevention and reducing credit risk); and  
(d) to the purchaser (or prospective purchaser) of any business or asset which we are (or are contemplating) selling.  
Except as provided in this privacy policy, we will not provide your information to third parties.

## INTERNATIONAL DATA TRANSFERS

Information that we collect may be stored and processed in and transferred between any of the countries in which we operate in order to enable us to use the information in accordance with this privacy policy.

Information which you provide may be transferred to countries (including the United States, Japan and other countries) which do not have data protection laws equivalent to those in force in the European Economic Areas (EEA).

In addition, personal information that you submit for publication on the website will be published on the internet and may be available, via the internet, around the world. By submitting this information you expressly agree to such transfers of it.

## SECURITY OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA

We will take reasonable technical and organisational precautions to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal information.

We will store all the personal information you provide on our secure (password- and firewall- protected) servers.

Of course, data transmission over the internet is inherently insecure, and we cannot guarantee the security of data sent over the internet.

You are responsible for keeping your password and user details confidential. We will not ask you for your password.

## YOUR RIGHTS

If you are a European resident, you have the right to access personal information we hold about you and to ask that your personal information be corrected, updated, or deleted. If you would like to exercise this right, please contact us at tom@caws.ws.

## MINORS

The Site is not intended for individuals under the age of 13.

## CHANGES

We may update this privacy policy from time to time in order to reflect, for example, changes to our practices or for other operational, legal or regulatory reasons.

## CONTACT US

For more information about our privacy practices, if you have questions, or if you would like to make a complaint, please contact us by e-mail at tom@caws.ws.

Parts of this Privacy Policy were generated by the Privacy Policy Generator of the [DGD - Your External DPO](https://dg-datenschutz.de/services/external-data-protection-officer/?lang=en) that was developed in cooperation with [German Lawyers](https://www.wbs-law.de/eng/) from WILDE BEUGER SOLMECKE, Cologne.

Parts of this Privacy Policy are courtesy of [Employment Law Contracts](http://www.employmentlawcontracts.co.uk/) and [Website Law](http://www.website-law.co.uk/)
